# Elrey C. Belmonti

Junior Developer

# Personal Info

Phone

267.325.2985

E-mail

elbelmonti@gmail.com

**Portfolio** 

elrey.info

**GitHub** 

https://github.com/ElreyB

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/elreyb/

Being a passionate people-person with over 10 years of experience as a professional dancer and in the hospitality industry; bringing tech and communities together is a dedication of mines. After a year and a half sabbatical, wire jewelry making and briefly attending Dev Bootcamp, I attended and graduated from Epicodus' 6 month program building web applications from scratch. Coding over a year and finishing my internship I am enthusiastic to bring my fullstack skills to your team/company.

## **Education**

2017-08 -

## **Epicodus**

2018-02

- Lead by example/influence and deliver ideas compellingly
- Created an interactive learning tool that allows children the ability to create a personalized approach to learning
- Initiated a communication tool that streamlined information sharing and event planning for the class

2016-09 -

#### **Dev Bootcamp**

2017-05

- Increased my knowledge in Practical Object Oriented Design in Ruby and algorithms
- Coached relieving stress techniques to peers
- Actively participated in Engineer Empathy lectures

# **Projects**

## Vespolina Evento; Rails, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap

Vespolina Evento is an app that makes it easier to request reservation for an event at Vespolina. Live Site:https://peaceful-eyrie-37050.herokuapp.com/,

Github: https://github.com/ElreyB/vespolina-evento

#### Generator; Angular 5, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

ChalkDoc application to generate worksheets for math teachers. Live Site: https://generator.chalkdoc.com/, Github: https://github.com/ElreyB/generator

#### **Epic-Goose (Group Project); HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap**

Conceptualized and served as team lead on a choose your own journey story application following the story of "Goblin Market".

Live site: https://elreyb.github.io/epic-goose/, Github: https://github.com/ElreyB/epicgoose

# **Experience**

2018-01 -

#### Intern

2018-02

ChalkDoc

- Identify and addressed tech debt
- Organized daily goals
- Refactored existing code base using higher order functions & reduced total source lines of code by 60%
- Ensured consistent and thorough documentation

#### 2005-09 -

## Manager, Host, Event Planner

2015-11

Hospitality Industry

- Full cycled event planning for parties up to 100 people
- Comfortable working with high-end clienteles, including celebrities and corporations
- Solidified relationships with repeat clients to deliver their party vision to reality
- Single-handedly created host manuals and trainings for four [high end] restaurants

### 2002-04 -2015-10

## **Dancer, Choreographer**

Dance Companies In Philadelphia and Seattle Area

- Established a large network in the dance community
- Participated in several dance companies that exchanged dance concepts with international companies
- Lead classes in modern dance and yoga for local communities